Kaitlyn Patton

7140 Alum Creek Avenue Las Vegas, NV 89178 | (702)430-1099 | kaitlynpatton@yahoo.com

Professional Summary

Animal-loving college student with one-year experience working in animal care and another in volunteering at shelters. Focused and dedicated to expanding my knowledge on animal science and biology, along with pursuing a career in Veterinary Medicine in the future.

Education

2017 - 2021 | Colorado State University

- · Bachelor's in biomedical sciences in Biology
- Plans on applying to Colorado State University's Doctor of Veterinary Medicine program a year upon graduation.

Skills & Abilities

- · Ability to perform well under pressure and high stress situations.
- · Continuous drive and willingness to learn and expand my knowledge.
- · Ability to maintain excellent communication with coworkers and customers.
- · Capable of performing a task as a team, as well as individually.
- · Experience in caring for and the handling of animals.
- · High interest in learning biology and components of the veterinarian field.

Experience

Sales Associate | Charlotte Russe Inc. – Las Vegas, NV | 05/2017 - 12/2017

- · Demonstrated use and care of merchandise.
- · Prioritized and accomplished a wide range of tasks each shift.
- · Stocked shelves and supplies, along with organizing displays.
- · Organized racks and shelves to maintain the visual appeal of the store.
- · Greeted customers and ascertained customers' needs.
- · Always kept work areas clean and neat.
- Developed positive customer relationships through friendly greetings and excellent service.
- Maintained an up-to-date knowledge of product and service offerings to serve as an informational resource to customers and coworkers.
- · Answered questions regarding the store and its merchandise.
- Accepted and processed returns.
- · Worked collaboratively in team environments.

Pets Hotel Associate | PetSmart inc. – Las Vegas, NV | 06/2018 - 07/2018

- · Provided pet owners with excellent customer service and compassionate care for their pets.
- · Managed and ensured pet safety and wellness in owners' absence.

- · Communicated with clients to provide pet status during overnight or vacation care.
- · Followed all pet care instructions, including dietary needs and medication regiments.
- · Cleaned kennels, animal holding areas, and play areas.
- Groomed dogs and cats by utilizing tools including brushes, combs, shedding aids, de-matting tools, and nail clippers or grinders.
- Relieved boredom and stress of staying in a pet hotel environment by walking, playing, and tending to dogs and cats. Recorded activity and noted any unusual behavior or medical issues that occurred.
- · Monitored Doggy Day Camp sessions to make sure all dogs were all well behaved, hydrated, and well fed.

Delivery Driver & Pizza Artist | Cozzola's Pizza – Fort Collins, CO | 03/2019 - 03/2020

- · Followed driving security and protection policies and procedures.
- · Helped take phone calls, placing orders, and performing prep work in the kitchen.
- · Washed dishes, flatware, pots, and pans by hand.

Kennel Attendant | West Russel Animal Hospital – Las Vegas, NV | 04/2021 – 05/2021

- · Kept animals clean and free of contaminants to promote optimal health.
- · Mixed and administered special food formulas to individual animals based on their dietary needs.
- · Maintained clean and organized boarding areas and kennels to promote animal wellbeing.
- · Ability to perform safe and efficient animal handling techniques.
- · Knowledge of kennel procedures and operations.
- · Assisted Veterinarians, Vet techs and assistants when help was needed.